TROMER SEBASTIAN ELECTRONICS ENGINEER

Date of Birth 24. June 1986 (Age 28)

Nationality Argentinian

Languages Spanish, English, German

Location Mendoza. Argentina

Email tromersebastian@gmail.com

Online CV tromex.github.io

Linkedin ar.linkedin.com/in/tromersebastian



ABSTRACT

For the last decade I have been studying and developing skills in different areas of Electronics Engineering. My experience on the field was achieved by working on different University projects of software and hardware development.

I also worked for 7 months as Hardware and Firmware Engineer for a company dedicated to design and manufacture meteorological stations mainly focused on Vineyards.

I can communicate fluently in English and I'm working to do it in German. Because I lived and studied in Germany for 6 months in context of a DAAD scholarship, I have given speeches in English in public and also I have been taking German courses since 5 years ago.

My goal is to work in an environment that allows me to acquire new knowledge and experience in new technologies; in innovative projects in which I can grow professionally and personally; preferably in an international environment.

My main areas of interest are: Control Systems, Internet of Things, Artificial Intelligence, Robotics.

EXPERIENCE

WORK EXPERIENCE

International border web application monitor

Dirección Nacional de Vialidad (Universidad Tecnológica Nacional) Dec 2014 - Apr 2015

- Web application, for internal and public use, showing meteorological information and real-time camera photos across two international borders.
- Database synchronization with 3rd party external application of meteorological stations.
- **Technologies:** Python, Web2py, D3.js, Javascript, jQuery, git, MySQL, SQL Server 2008, HTML5, CSS3.

Meteorological stations

Innova Soluciones Informáticas S.R.L.

2010 - 2011 (7 months)

- Improvements made on older hardware to reduce power consumption.
- Communication of analog sensors data through RS485 to central board.
- Communication of digitalized data to GSM/GPRS Telit modem.
- Signal conditioning for PT100 Precision Temperature Sensor.
- Project planning for development of ultrasonic anemometer.
- Requirements paperwork in order to apply for Government funds. Funds successfully received.
- Technologies: Microchip PIC16F876A, MPLAB, MPASM, RS232, RS485, PT100.

Electronic voting system

Honorable Legislatura de Mendoza (Universidad Tecnológica Nacional) 2007 - 2010

- Implemented voting system in C#.
- Communication though RS232 with external voting Hardware.
- Automatic generation of reports using Reporting Services.
- Display in external screens using Adobe Flash.
- 2 Years of System maintenance.
- **Technologies:** Microsoft Visual Studio, C#, Microsoft Reporting Services, Adobe flashscript, RS232.

FAT16 implementation for SD cards in PIC16

CEGA Electronics S.A.

2008

- Interface with SD card using PIC MSCP module in SPI mode. Programmed in MPASM.
- SD Formatting in FAT16. Creation and writing of files. Programmed in Microchip C18.
- Technologies: Microchip PIC16F876A, MPLAB, MPASM, Microchip C18.

ACADEMIC RESEARCH

- Implementation of an energy efficient indoor localization algorithm
- RED SIPIA (Wireless Sensor Network)
- Learning tool for IEEE 802.15.4

OTHER PROJECTS

- PIC Datalogger with SD card / FAT16 support
- Low speed Analog Datalogger through Ethernet
- 1.5 MHz Analog signal capturer board
- Low frequency DSSS generator with PIC
- CESSNA C172P Automatic pilot for FlightGear simulator
- Neuroproductivo

EDUCATION

Electronics Engineer

Facultad Regional Mendoza - Universidad Tecnológica Nacional - Argentina 2004 - 2015

Studienarbeit

Technische Universität Dresden - Germany Sep 2009 - Feb 2010

- Project: "Implementation of an energy efficient indoor localization algorithm"
- Studienarbeit defended in English. Note: 1.3

German Course (B2.1 - B2.2)

Sociedad Goetheana de Mendoza (Goethe Institut Partner) - Argentina 2014

German Course (B2.1)

Institute of Advanced Studies (TUDIAS) - TU Dresden - Germany Sep 2009 - Feb 2010

PUBLICATIONS

Enabling Low-power Localization for Mobile Sensor Nodes

IEEE - Indoor Positioning and Indoor Navigation (IPIN) 2010

Link: Go to IEEE Xplore Digital Library

A Low-Power Scheme for Localization in Wireless Sensor Networks

EUNICE'10 Proceedings of the 16th EUNICE/IFIP WG 6.6 conference on Networked services and applications: engineering, control and management / Editor: Springer-Verlag Berlin

Link: Go to Springer Link

A High Configurable Protocol for Indoor Localization Systems

IEEE - 2011 International Conference on Indoor Positioning and Indoor Navigation (IPIN)

Link: Go to IEEE Xplore Digital Library

COMMUNICATION SKILLS

Spanish Mother tongue

English Professional working proficiency
German Limited working proficiency (B2)